all right everybody we are back
it is jack murphy this is the jack
murphy live podcast
you can find me on twitter at jack
murphy live at the website
jackmurphylive.com
go to amazon get my book democrat to
deplorable why nine million democrats
ditched a why nine million obama voters
ditched the democrats and embraced
donald trump in 2016.
and if you want to learn more about the
liminal hyphen order that is
our all men's organization dedicated to
our three core values of
masculinity brotherhood and sovereignty
check it out liminal hyphen order dot
com
but enough about me today is all about
the man of the moment right now it seems
like christopher ruffo chris how you
doing buddy
i'm doing good you know i didn't didn't
sleep too much last night was
in a pretty celebratory mood very
excited uh but it's good to be with you
this morning
yeah fantastic thanks you know we've
been trying to get this arranged for a
couple of months now
and uh boy did we get this thing
scheduled at the right time because dude
you are
literally blowing up all over the place
you're doing tremendous work
you're having a real impact it must be a
lot of fun you having fun right now
yeah i am you know that's the thing i
feel like i'm just having a great time
i'm doing what i'm supposed to be doing
and
once you kind of click into that i feel
like anything is possible
indeed once you align yourself with your
core values align yourself to the values
of the universe
everything starts to get easier when
you're doing good and doing well all the
same time
it's a fantastic feeling and you know
kudos to you and congratulations for
that i've been watching this and it's
been really impressive and
for me it has a personal your work has a
personal connection for me because
i have been working on talking about
writing about critical race theory
wokism social justice warriors radical
feminism
intersectionality marxism how all these
things have come together
uh for years now and uh you know i
dedicated chapters and chapters in my
book to this subject written in 2017
and uh for me personally it's just been
amazing to see
all this come to the forefront right now
at this time
and uh you know you're helping lead the
charge swords up
which i love and i hope we can all adopt
that because
that's where we need to be right now
sort of wartime mode yeah and
going out and attacking attacking so
what what i like to do
on jack murphy live here this is long
form this is not gonna be
clicks out you know quick sound bites i
wanna know about you bud like i've been
watching
your work uh but you know i and i think
a lot of listeners don't know you
personally
and that's i wanna start with that you
know i want to find out
your perspective your setting your
context for this work and then we'll
build up
uh to your recent work and your success
and talk about what it means for the
country so
can you give us a little bit of
background man like how did you get into
journalism where are you from
where'd you go to school you know how
did you get how did you get into the
point where you could start doing this
kind of work
yeah well my my path is is not a
is not a common one and maybe not even a
recommended one but um
you know i grew up in california uh in
sacramento uh
my father's an immigrant from italy uh
my mom was a
daughter of a automotive engineer uh
from detroit
and uh i grew up in this kind of um you
know very kind of progressive atmosphere
it's california
we're kind of a stone's throw away from
berkeley and that for a long time was my
reference point i kind of
saw myself as a as a young man of the
left
um you know was uh you know kind of
protesting in high school
and uh and kind of you know kind of like
embracing all of those things looking at
all the videos from
berkeley 1968 and uh and that was really
kind of my
frame of reference and and uh you know
we're talking before the show i i went
to georgetown for my undergraduate
degree
and um you know that's kind of where
things like
politically fell apart for me and uh
it's you know i got involved with some
of the kind of
left lefty campus organizations and i
remember sitting in like some
meeting or some subcommittee uh
and these kind of like very affluent
very privileged people were
you know organizing a hunger strike on
behalf of some cause and
it just felt so phony to me that's the
thing that that happened and really kind
of my
disillusionment with left politics was
really
at first personal saying wait a minute
this doesn't make sense
these people are total phonies it's like
it's kind of a performance to satisfy
their own kind of
status needs or social desires has
nothing to do with actually helping real
people so
i kind of like just clicked out of
politics altogether
um i and then i kind of chanced on a job
working on a documentary film crew and
spent the next decade uh traveling
around the world producing documentaries
for pbs
for netflix for oh wow japanese tv for
other broadcasters
um and uh i just wanted to kind of hit
the streets and go out in the world have
some adventure
i certainly did and uh and then kind of
through kind of study of the actual
world as it is
through kind of my own academic study um
i kind of started drifting
towards the right the ideas made sense
to me um
and then having a family and kind of
getting a bit deeper
sense of what's meaningful i started
kind of
you know drifting rightward in my own
private life
but then very much silent publicly
because the documentary world as you
could imagine is
very progressive and very intolerant
um and then about two years ago i made
this i made the decision
i'm done being silent i'm done being
just uh
kind of kind of putting my tail between
my legs and uh
and decided to bust out was there was
there a moment was there something that
happened was there an event
where you finally were like all right
that's it i've had enough
i yeah i just saw the end i saw the end
of the road in my documentary career
and uh you know as far as documentary
careers go mine was a very successful
one
um on the outside but on the inside i
just felt um
i felt restricted i felt kind of
confined i felt
like i couldn't express myself in a
really meaningful way and i was kind of
trapped in this
kind of really kind of brutal and angry
and depressive industry um that was
you know had become over the years hyper
ideological
and and uh and that's kind of when i
realized that i think i was maybe
on on vacation with my wife and actually
my father we went back to our village in
italy
and um and i kind of just had a moment
where i realized
this is the end of this i can't keep
going this way i'm going to be deeply
unhappy
um and then i kind of started scrounging
around to try to figure out hey how can
i kind of politically engage and
you know one of the first steps was
doing a claremont fellowship and i did
the
lincoln fellowship and uh and you know
it's funny because
they they actually called me they said
hey we really like your application
we kind of don't know who you are we
kind of maybe think you're a left-wing
plant
um can you can you prove to us that
you're actually
a conservative because you're like a
documentary guy uh
and and you know it worked out and i'm
very close with all those guys now but
uh
but it was really kind of like a rough
transition you know just
uh uh you know just to kind of get out
of one world and into another
yeah i i completely understand that if
you don't speak your truth especially in
an industry like documentary filmmaking
which
i think is about getting truth out right
and telling stories and telling people's
personal stories or
there's a variety of subjects but really
it's about revealing something to the
audience and
if you're in an industry like that and
you can't express your true thoughts and
your true self that must be
i mean it's stifling and and suppressive
and oppressive to anybody
but then doubly so a creative person
with
ideas and opinions and the means by
which to express themselves so
i completely understand that i had
similar experiences i just simply could
not
keep my mouth shut over time and you
know i
i think we probably have a little bit of
a similar vibe in that i've kind of been
a vigilante a lot of my life where if i
see something that's wrong
i have to say something or i have to fix
it or
and you know when it's your own truth
it's like you gotta just get it out man
you just gotta get it out and if you
don't you kind of go crazy
i i remember i interviewed a guy a while
back and he said that he had a
like an uncontrollable urge to express
himself and i think that that's part of
what makes somebody get into journalism
or art or something like that so
interesting point on the claremont
fellowship we talked about it right
before the show i did not know that
about you
i tend to uh gravitate towards the
claremont guys i think we have a lot of
overlapping
uh world views and opinions and brian
williams and those guys are fantastic
uh and i've got another claremont guy
coming up
next week and another one after that now
that i think about it so
uh claremont definitely doing great work
out there
uh and and i wonder too who wrote the
we'll get to this but who wrote the
actual uh president's order because it
reads like somebody from claremont had
written it so it's a it's very well done
and i love that
i too went to georgetown a school
foreign service just like you
and it was interesting to me there to
see i got the full dose of globalism
multiculturalism the whole thing
identity politics and when it's coming
from
the richest most elite most successful
exclusive people in the whole world
it is uh it's especially grating uh to
deal with at the time
i wasn't super clear on how it was all
working out for me but now i look back
and i'm glad that i got that education
but
uh you know i certainly don't hold the
same views
as what was pumped into me at georgetown
so all right you're a documentary
filmmaker you're literally traveling
around the world doing stuff for big
names and and
great projects and you decide to make a
change
and that change is to get into
journalism so where did you go how did
you start
you know what was the first step where
was your first where'd you land first
like how did you get the ball rolling
here
yeah you know uh kind of like a series
of of events you know i'm
you know been in seattle and in the
seattle area the last six years so not
exactly kind of a dc
to new york corridor place we're
actually way out there
um but a a mentor of mine a guy named
bruce chapman
um who was the census director for
ronald reagan started a think tank here
in seattle
and um and he said hey chris you know
you've been you know making this
documentary on american poverty
you know you'd be great at looking into
the kind of doing a policy paper
or kind of a long essay on homelessness
in the pacific northwest
um and i said yeah i've been meaning to
kind of move more politically this is
great so he you know
provided kind of a small grant to write
this
article essentially a long long kind of
feature magazine article
and uh and i finished it i wrote it i
was pretty happy with it and then
i had met reihan salam who was then the
editor of national review
we had met because i had done a
documentary on the uyghur
muslim minorities of china um and uh we
had kind of exchanged information
and i said man i don't know anyone
except for this guy rey hunts along
so i sent it to him and he said hey this
is not a good fit for us but let me
connect you with city journal at
manhattan institute
and um and then they published the piece
and then
um you know kind of blew up i think like
they
you got shared a hundred thousand times
on city journal's website which is
actually kind of a lot for a policy
magazine and then uh shortly after that
you know
they said hey come out to new york talk
talk to us and uh and then they said hey
why don't you you know become a
contributing editor for the magazine
and uh and that's really kind of the
start of all this and
i think you know i had like no formal
journalism training a kind of
you know in a way self-taught but the
thing about making a documentary is like
you learn all of the essential
journalism skills and honestly i think
you actually learn them better than
99 of journalists because when you're
making a film you have to gain
very deep access with people you have to
negotiate to be in their life
over months and sometimes years you have
to get all of their thoughts and
feelings out you have to do it in front
of a camera
in front of lights on in front of a
microphone um
and then you actually have to like put
yourself out there you know it's like
i've been thrown off a horse and broke
my ribs and the
tigers of mongolia i've been arrested by
chinese secret police and xinjiang
like you know doing some political
reporting
isn't really gonna you know phase me in
any way so
you got arrested by the secret police in
china yeah man if you're making a
documentary in china about the uyghurs
uh
whoa tell us that story man yeah well
you know
we kind of um it was 2008
uh and i was kind of working on my
second film i was looking at this
actually a beautiful story
um and it's available on my website for
free for folks who want to see it
um i think it's still for free um but
you know making this beautiful story
there's kind of the the the han
chinese the kind of dominant ethnic
chinese
um and then there's the the the uyghur
uh minority
in the kind of northwest kind of far
west of china
and and and now it's absolutely horrific
i couldn't make a film there now
uh they've they've put essentially more
than a million maybe two million uh
uyghurs into
what can really be called kind of
re-education or concentration camps
and these are these are two groups that
that have nothing in common china kind
of annex
their territory um they've repressed
this uh minority group for for many
years since the 1949 i believe
and yet the story that i was telling was
this one baseball team
that had uh you know they were the only
baseball team in a thousand miles in any
direction
and they had been inspired by jackie
robinson to have a multi-ethnic baseball
team
really one of the only places where the
kind of they cross these segregation
lines
and then at the end of the year they
play one game a year against a team of
tibetans in the tibetan highlands
um so it's this kind of like epic uh
story and journey
and um you know i was very young at the
time
and uh and and a couple times really one
time that was actually quite scary
uh you know detained by kind of you know
uniformed and sometimes
plain close uh chinese security and uh
kind of dragged into a basement of a
police precinct
uh walking past looking at uh the kind
of iron chairs with the
the the the arm and the leg cuffs
thinking oh
i might not come out of here
um but you know what what i did was like
um
kind of by instinct and then in
retrospect kind of brilliant where
you know um i just played um i kind of
pretended to be a dumb
american surfer dude tourist and just
kind of
you know answered their questions in the
kind of dumbest way possible
until they got frustrated with me they
held us for a couple hours and then they
let us go
um but uh but um yeah so that's you know
that's the kind of thing that happens
you know
so you've been you've been laying it on
the line for the stories that you think
are important that the world needs to
know
for some time now so this is like this
is who you are man we
when you were growing up were you uh
fighter were you
vigilante did you always right the
wrongs
always yeah and it's something like it's
crazy you know i feel like
i was always fighting um like not not
physically i mean sometimes physically
if i had to but um but you know
typically not i'm not
i'm not a particularly big or or uh
physically intimidating person but i was
always fighting intellectually
um i was always kind of um uh you know
trying to look at the world trying to
see what was wrong with it and then
trying to
fix it and i think that really got
beaten out of me for a long time
um in the documentary world kind of just
the rhythm of business in the
documentary world it's kind of these
long multi-year projects um
the industry itself is kind of kind of
kind of constrictive
culturally and then i i just feel like
um
you know in my 20s i just kind of was
living a pretty
extreme lifestyle frankly um
but yet like not really channeling it
into a fight for some
justice or some good uh in a real kind
of visceral way
and uh and i think like i i miss that
and uh
and i um you know i may not have been as
effective a fighter at 23 as i am now
but certainly like kind of re-emerging
into this in the last
two years really since i've engaged
politically
has been great and sometimes people are
born to fight
and that's just how you are your nature
and i think i
maybe even denied that nature for some
time i kind of tried to put it in a box
or people tell you oh you shouldn't do
that or you're an
or or you know you're this or
you're that and
people kind of shame you out of it um
and then you know i kind of hit this
acid test where it's like
when you come out as a kind of
conservative writer intellectual
political figure
in a very liberal city on the west coast
um you have no choice but to fight
and uh no and honestly i'm loving it
it's like i feel like rejuvenated you
know
yeah no kidding man i have had very very
similar experiences
out here uh i found myself working in
education
uh sort of by accident sort of through
the back door of real estate because i
was a real estate developer and i got
into
running charter schools and uh before i
knew it i became executive director of
charter schools in washington dc and i
became a turnaround expert school
turnaround expert
where i would get hired to turn around
the worst performing charter school
systems in the district of columbia
and i was able to do it once not even
just once but twice actually
and actually almost three times so like
it became a passion and a mission for me
fighting for people that didn't have a
voice and fighting to ju you know
to change and and solve wrongs to right
wrongs and
to help people that needed help and
needed a voice and i found the work to
be
so uh rewarding and engaging
and then we were successful and then
people found out long story me getting
doxed by antifa
but people found out that i was writing
about conservative issues through a pen
name you know writing about
sanctuary cities writing about radical
feminism doing satirical takes on
radical feminism to mock them
uh and and and covering covering i would
go as an independent journalist and
cover
alt-right events and and and antifa
fights in the square and from the white
house
and just because i was there people
thought i was a nazi and then they
they wanted to destroy me so they did
they attacked me they destroyed me
they got me fired from from my job they
took away
all the things i had worked for all the
good work i was doing
simply because i had a slightly
right of center you know or now it's
probably considered radical right i
don't even know
uh perspective you know which is
basically that like
we were all created equal everybody
should have equal chance and equal
opportunity and let's make sure that
that that happens
not that everybody needs to be the same
and we need to make that happen which is
pretty much
the dividing line right now so in
washington dc i have
to fight every day as well uh and it's
been a challenge personally
i'm sure you've had similar experience
out there with sort of your old life and
old friends now
this is all public has that have you had
any schisms like in your social life or
family or do people like look down on
what you're doing now has it
damaged your relationships in any way
yeah you know
that's a it's a good question i i think
i with family definitely not my family's
very proud of me my family is
so supportive of anything i do and and
they just want to see me happy
and i think that they've seen me uh
really emerge and into myself and
and and just feel happy and so they're
very supportive my grandmother
who is a 93 um she's actually a big
progressive she's very far left she
always has been
kind of getting on more protesting and
and all that and uh but she's even happy
for me she's uh
she's like i seen you on the tucker
carlson i i really don't like that guy
but you did great
so so the family is great and my friends
are great and yeah i lost friendships
for sure
i lost friendships i lost funders i lost
you know creative collaborators oh i
can't work with this guy anymore
um but i'll tell you what for every
friend that i lost
i gained 10 much stronger friends um and
and that's the thing and it's like you
know it's so funny because it's like hey
we were friends for
years and i tolerated and accepted and
respected your
uh political opinions you just didn't
know mine because you never asked
uh and then you know when the tables
turn just even slightly
um you know you're unable to show that
same kind of toleration
uh or kind of respect and uh and i think
that's a shame but it really kind of
weeds out the people who are truly your
friend from the people who aren't and
i still have a lot of friends that are
on the left and we're still great
friends and
and and kind of razz each other and it's
it's good fun uh because we can see that
there's like a world and a life outside
of politics but
right you know through the political
activism i guess or political writing
um i've made a lot of great friends very
strong friends and and one thing i think
is you know
helpful to me and anyone who's listening
that finds themselves kind of marooned
or stranded in a big blue city
um you know i set up a group of about 10
guys
all kind of conservative men in seattle
and uh
we'd have monthly kind of off the record
private dinners uh and uh you know we'd
get a private room at a restaurant
we'd uh kind of you know talk trash and
and
and talk business and talk politics and
talk family uh and we all had the same
perspective and it just felt like
um every month you'd have that kind of
backstop and that kind of support that
kind of community and that kind of place
just
just to talk and it's like astonishing
that we're in
2020 the united states of america the
first amendment on paper is standing
strong
but the culture that we have is is
extremely
kind of repressive and you almost feel
like if you are anywhere outside of the
most kind of rigid
ideological progressivism you're a
dissident uh and and for a while
that bothered me um this is not fair and
you know kind of moped and pouted about
it
uh but then you kind of just have to
buck up and say that's the world as it
is that's reality
are you gonna kind of like cry about it
or you're gonna go about
accepting it and then changing it um and
that's the thing dude yeah that's it
that's all you got to do amen to that i
mean you basically just described the
mission statement of the liminal order
uh but we don't just do it in one city
we actually we actually have hundreds of
men
all across the country uh doing
virtually what you described right there
plus a whole lot more
uh we've got chapters in probably 15 to
20 cities across the country we've got
meetings all the time
and it's just the same thing you're
describing which is like finding a place
to relate to people that share your
world view
at a time in which there's just
seemingly chaos and negative energy
all around you so guys out there if that
sounds
good to you and it sounds interesting
check it out liminal hyphen order dot
com it's exactly what chris is talking
about
and a lot more but there is an urge to
to
gather up to squad up and to get with
like-minded men and
to build a community uh because you know
communities
strong men strong family strong
communities strong nation hopefully
is really the goal there uh so that's
interesting to hear that you've had
similar experiences and sought out
similar solutions
uh to the same circumstances that i had
so
we've got you now you're you're in the
game
you're working on uh you're working with
city journal
how is it that we come to critical race
theory
yeah so for city journal like the last i
guess almost two years now wow
i've been covering kind of west coast
disorder so i've been covering
homelessness addiction mental illness
crime
kind of hyper progressivism defunding
the police
all of these kind of urban issues so
that's been my beat i've done a
ton of work in that area and the
critical race theory stuff was something
i'd seen
emerging in practice in the documentary
world in the documentary world there are
kind of these siloed programs they're
kind of race-based
um kind of in some ways uh kind of
racially siloed programs um the the
ideology at the conferences i was going
to
was was very much a kind of identity
politics
matched with kind of grievance and
redistribution where documentary
filmmakers would be like i'm not making
any money making my movies like someone
should give me other people's money
and it's like dude like what you're
you're like a 40 year old man what are
you doing you know and uh and then the
identity politics started getting really
strong to the point where
like if you look at the sundance film
festival the kind of pinnacle of
documentary
success like every film documentary and
maybe fiction although i'm more familiar
with documentary look at the last like
five years
every documentary that's entered the
competition at sundance that is shown
there
um is essentially an identity politics
ideological piece
i mean it is like so focused and
the irony is that like a film will go to
sundance right you think it's a big
success
it'll get on amazon and it'll have like
12 reviews
you know so these documentaries that are
like reaching a smaller and smaller
audience
because they're on a subject that most
people aren't engaged in
like a very hardcore kind of identity
issues um
and yet they're at the top of the kind
of prestige totem pole uh within the
within the documentary industry and
i just like kind of kind of realized
like this is a total
dead end and i i just um uh
kind of jump from there and i think you
know fast forward now a couple years
and critical race theory is kind of
coming up again in the news and
it all started with an anonymous tip i
got a tip from someone who said hey
city of seattle is holding racially
segregated civil rights trainings
and i just said wait a minute the office
of civil rights
theoretically would be fighting any
instance of segregation is actually
perpetuating institutional segregation
um and and uh i did a records request i
got all of the information
uh that story kind of blew up and then i
became this kind of
de facto like documents like
leaking kind of like a mailbox
and i started getting just hundreds and
hundreds of leaked messages about this
stuff
and i kind of realized very quickly
after that first story took off
um this is a hot story this has
fire this has energy i'm the i'm the
right person to handle it and i'm going
to make something out of this
i'm going to push this as far as i can
dude that is fantastic and i want to
i'm going to go back just a second but
we're going to pick up right at this
point
in in the film world and in the art
world
in general at least my recollection of
art
was that it the art was the dissident
side
right like art was the one that was
supposed to be pushing the envelope
you know questioning the establishment
challenging the narratives
but somehow so quickly it seems
is that this radical theory this radical
perspective of identity politics
has somehow taken over as the
establishment
mainstream yet the artistic people and
my old like you know libertarian raver
friends from the 90s you know they all
thinking now that they're still being
rebels and punks
uh but yet they're really like towing
this line so
you saw that in the art world have you
seen that what do you make of this sort
of
the fact that like the quote there's no
dissident art
yeah that's exactly right and i think
it's you know to to me like there's some
great
and not to minimize the accomplishments
of some of my you know former
colleagues there are some great films or
some great filmmakers um but yeah i
think that the in the kind of
institutions and the structures um they
see themselves as kind of like on the
vanguard on the forefront of something
but it's like hey the stuff that you're
pushing is indistinguishable
uh from the stuff that they're pushing
in every fortune 500 company
kind of human rights our human uh
resources office uh it's
indistinguishable
what you see in hollywood in media and
in the foundations like
you're not taking actually any risk
because everyone
from the new york times to the ford
foundation already agrees with you
you're just kind of replicating they're
basically just replicators they take
some kind of dominant ideology
um which they kind of mistakenly think
is kind of edgy or progressive
and then they just kind of unconsciously
replicate it through kind of hundreds
and thousands of these stories
and um i just find it like honestly just
pathetic and it's like
what's the point what are we doing like
another one of these come on people
like let's push a little bit and uh and
i think that you know
in in a way the kind of in a way it's
it's frustrating right but in a way i
came to terms with it because i said
you know when was kind of like dissident
writing or dissident art
ever kind of funded and supported by the
establishment that's just not how it
works
right and and in order to to truly push
you have to be willing to take risks
um and and i think that that is really
the whole ball game you have to put
yourself
out there kind of into the maw of these
of these institutions that have the kind
of financial and cultural power to
obliterate
you and and that's it i mean you have to
be able to kind of
spiritually just shove yourself out
there into the gears
and just say i'm strong enough i'll be
able to take it and
that's not what you get in most of the
kind of art world what you get right now
is a kind of like
kind of followers lackeys uh kind of
my my nieces kind of generators um
and uh and that's cool i mean you know
but it's indistinguishable from
you know being a you know nine to five
or somewhere kind of doing what the boss
tells you um
you know it really is the same mindset
the same patterns and uh i think that
it's much more fun
to be on the outside pushing in yeah 100
it's way more fun doing that i came to
the same point here now where i'm
independently funded i'm
totally uncancelable i'm anti-fragile
i'm doing exactly what i love working on
this mission
same similar uh as you uh and you're
right you do just have to stick yourself
into the mall of the machine
you have to be willing to get ground up
i got ground up first and then that sort
of gave me a superpower of like being
uncancelable and then when and and like
yourself when you
uh when i see myself take take action
that that
you know takes a little bit of courage
or strength people just fall
right in behind because they want to
support you and they want to support
acts of courage and and acts of of real
critical thinking and actual real work
and taking challenges and taking risks
and so you know kudos to you i knew as
soon as we made contact on twitter
and started observing each other that we
would have uh
good energy and like similar similar
vibes um
and i'm really glad to in talking to you
now really this is the first time we've
talked uh
that it's being confirmed for me because
uh i feel i can feel that energy dude
and it's it's like it's something that
people
want to get behind because we're all
looking for for leadership we're all
looking for people to
uh answer the question of like what are
we gonna do about what are we gonna do
about this
and uh you've really taken the ball and
just started running with it so
let's let's latch back into the story
now the
the seattle stuff the washington stuff
what is the time period
that that happens like what is the
context
uh sort of the national context you know
where were we
in the riots or george floyd or portland
or whatever
like give us some context on when that
person reached out to you in seattle and
you started pushing that story oh my god
i don't even remember it's like it's
been such a blur so
i reported um on the seattle on july 8th
of this year okay um so it's been so
fast
july what what how long wait is that
like two and a half months
yeah yeah 90 days let's say because i
worked on it a little bit before july
8th
so it was really like a bl honestly
looking back it's kind of like i'm in
that like cartoon where the like wind is
blowing against you and your face is
like pulling back it's like
it's been like a rocket ride but um
it's basically 90 days and uh and i
think like
uh looking back like it's been a wild
ride but i did my first report about
three months ago
on these critical race theory and
institutions and then i just kept
hammering at it and hammering at it and
hammering at it
developing news cycles breaking news
cycles managing news cycles
amplifying it on laura ingraham on
tucker carlson
on neil cavuto um getting it to that
kind of television audience
um and then just like at one point i
can't remember
exactly when i think maybe it was at the
beginning of august um i just visualized
it i just said
my goal and then i i publicly expressed
it on twitter and my friends
texted me they're like dude you're a
megalomaniac you're insane you're like
ridiculous like get out of here but i
just said hey i've
i've i'm going to persuade the president
of the united states to issue an
executive order
abolishing critical race during the
federal government that's my goal and
i'm gonna get it done
and i had this like just intuition that
like it was totally
possible like yes i mean i'm gonna do it
um and then kind of these it really i'll
kind of give you the story because it's
interesting the back story is
do it um so i'm pushing these stories
i'm pushing these stories i'm breaking
these new they're making this news
writing the context and analysis and
then um tucker's guys calls me
and you know i've been appearing on the
show the last year or a little bit
longer every you know month or so
and they said hey tucker is excited
about this he wants to do it but he
wants to basically do
a joint opening monologue with you um
just like putting this story out there
and then i said all right wow that's
that's big all right cool so i'll work
on something so i like
run to the office um drive up to seattle
i'm like typing it out all right we're
gonna get a teleprompter
um so i can kind of do the monologue
back and forth with him um
and then they call they say hey the
studio doesn't have a teleprompter we
can't get one to you
so tucker's gonna set it up and then you
basically need to do a three-minute
report
just ad-lib outlining all of the work
you've done and what you want to do
about it
and i'm kind of like my heart's pounding
it's like holy moly like
you know they have a teleprompter that's
easy to do you read
but then i just kind of like um i
remember i was in the studio and the guy
who runs the studio i won't tell you
which one you don't want to get him in
trouble he's also like a big
time kind of conservative guy in seattle
he's like oh man you got it just
get it you're there so i kind of just
like get in there i just kind of like
mentally just black out
and then i just start i just feel like
machine gun fire coming out of my mouth
and then um and then at the end i had
rehearsed the line i just says and i
call on the president to immediately
issue an executive order blah blah blah
i had rehearsed that line in my head and
i was like that's
that's the money line and then i had
this weird feeling after i was done i
just kind of like
kind of like clicked back in and then i
get texts from the producers like that
was amazing great job
and i was like i know for sure that the
president just watched that
um and uh and the next day i get a call
from the white house says
you know we want to make we want to take
action on this okay so
so i love how you tell a big long story
about tucker and the
teleprompter and your tunnel vision
which i i have had like i've
used to do muay thai fights and dude you
get in the ring you can't see
anything you black out there's just you
stop thinking it's your training totally
takes over and you just kind of go
i know that feeling but you tell this
very nice long passionate story about
tucker and then you're like yeah and
then the white house called
yeah i mean it's weird but it's it's a
weird experience i'm just kind of like
uh
who called you what did they say what
happened um you know the
the uh the the guy
called me and uh and he just said hey
you know i'm calling on on behalf of the
president
and uh and uh i think at this point i
might be able to say so you know as the
chief of staff and uh
and you know when you get a call from
the kind of the chief of staff to the
president of the united states you're
kind of like
i mean that's never happened to me
before so i was thinking like wow this
is cool i'm like
i'm like in my little my little house
here in
kind of rural washington state my kids
are around it's pretty early because
it's uh
west coast time and uh and then that was
the moment i was like all right
this is like it's on now um and uh and
you know
and they have a very capable team and uh
they're very kind and and
i provided you know the material that i
had and the insight and analysis i had i
kind of you know
gave them uh gave them what i had and
then let them run with it because um
uh i i you know kind of like my work was
done and i was doing like
kind of the handoff and i'll tell you
the white house like
i think it was like three days later the
omb issued the memo
basically saying no more of this in the
federal government it's over
three days and it's like i'm thinking if
you're a kind of observer of politics
you say
a jeb bush a president jeb bush would
have never done it
and certainly wouldn't have done it in
60 days in uh 65 hours
and uh and you know the thing about the
the president is and whatever your views
are of
on him i might have changed over time
but it's like he gets it done
he's unafraid to jump into the fights
that need to be fought
and uh and he pushed it and then the omb
kind of
um you know pushed it out it caused this
big kind of media cycle and firestorm
a bit worried i was going to get trashed
by everyone uh but i
emerged unscathed even though the new
york times and the post and npr all came
after it
um and then uh and then
kind of i did some kind of cleanup work
basically said hey a lot of these
agencies are still just violating this
order you can't do that it's against the
law it's unconstitutionally
it's kind of unconstitutional overreach
and then um
and then yesterday the kind of the the
the you know the 10 megaton bomb dropped
uh and it's a full executive order uh
and it
and it ex honestly i i kind of
visualized the goal and this
um extends well beyond it i mean they
really the white house uh policy team
the white house lawyers
they basically figured out how can we
push this out the furthest and and i'll
give you kind of a
a brief kind of encapsulated version if
you haven't seen it well let's
let's hold off on that because i want to
dig into the memo
in detail uh okay but like dude
when they call you from the white house
does it say like unavailable number or
does it say
the white house because i need to know
because i never answered my phone
you know it was just a 202 number um so
i
i think it was probably just a cell
phone and uh and i just kind of like
i and and uh you know i had kind of been
back and forth over email with people
overnight because they're like hey this
is like
this has people's attention this is
happening so when i saw the 202 i was
like all right i know
i don't really have many friends in dc
anymore so um
i know for sure that this is a call that
is coming that is quite important and
i'm gonna pick it up
better better take this one yeah totally
yeah all right all right so now okay
maybe i'll answer the next unknown 202
number call i get
um okay so when you engage with the
white house did you get any sense
uh or what was your sense of their like
pre-existing
knowledge of the problem uh and their
sort of
attitudes that preceded your work maybe
like did you get the idea that they
had been thinking about this or looking
at it working on it
wanting or like did this come out of the
blue for them
you know my sense and again i i didn't
ask directly so i can only give you my
kind of sense and interpretation but
my sense is that um you know people who
are involved in politics they know this
stuff
but it's kind of like in republican
circles and conservative circles has
been just like oh
we don't like this but there's nothing
we can do about it has been kind of the
general attitude
um you know we can cut taxes but we
can't fight a culture war uh that's kind
of like
the the kind of formula and my sense is
that
um you know the the president uh i don't
know if he is well versed in critical
race theory uh i
i i i kind of am skeptical that he that
he was i
i doubt it um you know because he's he's
a business guy he's like a bare knuckle
business guy a politic kind of like a
more visceral political creature
and my sense is that uh he saw it um
and he said this is a complete outrage
get it done
um and uh and i think you know you hear
stories about reagan
um in the same kind of vein uh you know
where he just would you know go into a
into a room they're having some big
meeting he says
i don't know when you know you figure it
out
and i think there's that same kind of
energy and same kind of decisiveness
um and uh and so i think that this is
really a totally new territory and uh
you know the the the writer for first
things mark bauerlein wrote yesterday
says for five decades conservatives have
been told that we can't stop identity
uh progressivism we can cut taxes we can
reduce regulation but we'll never win
these fights
and in his analysis i think it's true
this is really the first time
that we've successfully counter-attacked
and all credit
you know frankly goes to the president
um he's the person who just
made it happen and i don't think there's
really any other political figure with
maybe the exception of a josh hawley
um who would have taken that kind of
bold and decisive action
that is why i supported donald trump in
2016.
uh i saw the writing clearly on the wall
starting all the way back even for me
like 2010 is when i began this sort of
red pilling process and i started
pulling on the same
this one thread like what's up with
feminism
that was how i started all this i
started pulling on the same thread and
here i am 10 years later having this
conversation with you about this very
thing
where donald trump i mean this is why i
voted for the guy i can't
get over how excited i am that he's
actually taking on the culture war
head on uh in my book i
and i outline all this stuff about
critical race theory
social justice warriors
intersectionality it's history it's
fusion with marxism et cetera i've
talked to uh james lindsey
months before cynical theories came out
we went through the whole thing we
talked about it got it all out there for
everybody to understand
talked to ryan williams at claremont
president claremont talking about
you know the the the need to fight
multiculturalism
and and how you know basically we're at
flight you know flight 93 status on on
all sorts of fronts but one of them
including
fighting multiculturalism which has at
its root this idea these critical race
theory ideas
which is really just sort of now like an
umbrella term that that covers all kinds
of stuff but it has
metastasized since this very specific
thing
and that is why i voted for donald trump
i wanted him to fight the woke i saw
what was happening on college campuses i
interviewed
robbie soav who detailed uh you know
title ix
uh you know you know miss justices and a
lack of liberty all across the country
uh and you know i've been to evergreen
state college i went and spoke there
after brett weinstein got booted on that
whole fiasco
you know so like i went into the went
into the viper's den there
trying to talk about these things so you
know for me
i'm so excited to see you doing this and
for the president to have responded this
has been a mission a life's mission
for me for years now and that's why i
voted for trump among
other reasons but one was to fight the
woke and by golly he
is actually doing it now so let's uh
let's talk about
uh so the seattle thing takes off then
you have a couple of more big pieces
like
walk us through the timeline and then
let's get to the orders and then let's
dig into the orders because i want to
talk about exactly what's going to
happen there yeah
you know the the couple pieces that
stand out you know
some like smaller pieces i do on twitter
where it's like hey the fbi is holding a
weekly intersectionality workshop
like this is completely insane like they
shouldn't do this
but it wasn't like a full i didn't have
the documents for like a full
article um so i would kind of like
pepper the small stories into the
twitter kind of ecosystem
and those would immediately kind of like
replicate on the right
and then end up in news articles at
post-millennial or twitchy or some of
the kind of
very buzzy very social media
publications and then sometimes go up to
the the fox news the national review the
american conservative et cetera
um and then sometimes then bump up to
like a tucker carlson appearance
um but you know i did the treasury
department let's stop let's stop right
there because this is an interesting
phenomenon
talk about the the info ecosystem that
you just described
right like you source something you put
it out there and then describe the cycle
like
who picks it up and how like well this
is a very interesting and important
point
in our new media landscape and the way
that independent
uh journalists and and media people are
actually driving narratives in a way
that was never possible before so
yeah can you just describe that process
please yeah i'll i'll break it down it's
kind of like um
once you see it it's kind of like magic
when you sit on the outside it's kind of
like magic but then once you actually
understand the principles and forces
that play it's kind of like
oh it's just that so you know obviously
like
and and i only i honestly only engaged
in twitter for the last
maybe five six months i kind of just
wasn't on it for some reason but um
but you know twitter is kind of like the
lifeblood of media right now
i mean that's just that's just how it is
and um and then
and conservative media has its own kind
of world so
what you do is like what i would do is
i'll kind of say all right i have a
story i think it's going to be a heater
i think it's going to be hot
um i and i'll i'll basically write up a
twitter thread
embed some kind of documents and then at
the end i'll link to a story in city
journal
or new york post or whatever wherever
i'm writing so i'll have an op-ed length
piece that'll go into the bloodstream in
the kind of mainstream publications
i'll i'll drop a twitter thread that
kind of like
can go viral there and then i'll also
send out an email blast to my email list
which has a lot of journalists a lot of
producers
you know anytime i do a tv show or i
make sure to say hey can i put you on my
email list
so i know that all the kind of top
conservative producers in the country
are now on this list
so they'll see it either at new york
post or city journal
they'll see it on twitter that'll kind
of like replicate with there
or they'll see it um in my email list
and then
you know a big story will then get
bumped up to kind of the primetime tv
um and then and that audience is just
you cannot underestimate the power of
that
i mean like like like all of my aunt's
friends are like i saw you on tv
yesterday
you know what i mean i mean it is like
the audience is huge and like and tucker
is at the top of the pyramid
i mean he's getting like four million
people uh a night including a lot of the
policy people so
so if you can kind of what i think of it
is climbing the ladder
um so like some stories you climb the
first little part it's like a cool tweet
and then it dies
some stories you kind of climb up you
write it off bad then maybe it'll go to
new york post or the wall street journal
if that's like really nice
and then you try to keep climbing and
just try to ride it and then what
happens is
then if you hit a big story it starts to
take on a life of its own
and then you're like not in control
you're not fighting for stuff you're not
kind of like
actively pursuing it you're just
literally like writhing
riding this wave and this story the last
90 days has been like a tidal wave
and then you're like oh okay you know
the new york times is reaching out for
comment and then
you know yahoo is going to do a hit
piece on you and then washington post is
all is all mad about it and
you know someone wants to you to debate
them on npr and
like and then you're just kind of
managing appearances and managing
uh when you fight back when you ignore
um
and then and then really just trying to
kind of like just stay in the flow of
the story
and it's happened to me a number of
times in the last year um this is
obviously the biggest one but it is like
it's this weird and completely
terrifying like
surfing a like a hurricane wave
because like yeah you could get just you
could i mean these these institutions
could could rip into you man and it's
not fun
it's like it's really not fun when some
like the biggest publications of the
world rip into you
or someone's mad and so you're kind of
like trying to like get what you need to
get done but at a certain point you
realize
a lot of it's just out of my control and
you just have to kind of recognize what
you can control what you can't
uh and have the kind of wisdom to know
the difference
oh yeah that's good advice for all kinds
of things
uh that is uh an excellent example and
you know we we know that the guys at the
big media companies are all
you know the producers and this is
they're all on social media they're all
on our social medias they're all
following
us all the time looking for stories and
i've seen it just happened just time and
time and time again
i think one of the first times that i
really really watched it happen
was uh back in 2015 or early 2016 when
there were questions about hillary
clinton's health and you know the
genesis
of that story was on a small not so
small anymore blog
i think mike cernovich was running it
back then and it just it just went
wow man and it just took over the whole
new cycle and then from there you could
just see
took over the national conversations
even and then from there you can just
start to begin to see the ecosystem
and so you know when when people are on
twitter
and they feel like they're fighting for
something or they feel like they're
they're trying and i don't mean like
influencers i mean just like regular
people
they're trying to make a difference you
know they do
the the every little like every little
retweet
matters because the more it gets engaged
the more it gets promoted the more
people find it you get connected to
bigger nodes
it gains momentum it finds a bigger node
it gains even more momentum
and before you know it you're on tucker
carlson and
you're getting the president to take
action and so like
people in the audience out there like it
really helps the engagement
on stories that are meaningful and
important it really does make a
difference and i've seen it happen now
just countless times it's happened to me
not all the way to this scale just quite
yet but like i've seen
you know kicking off national stories
and news cycles for the day and just
you know it's a it's good motivation for
people to keep moving
out there and and we're really all in
this together folks
like audience and creators and
journalists we're all in it together
and uh thank you i want to say thank you
to everybody i know chris
is grateful and it really does help it
matters when you engage with the tweet
in a story and you promote it and you
share it
and you subscribe and you do whatever
you can it all
matters because the more people bring
attention to the subject the more likely
you know something is to get
accomplished so that's a that's a very
interesting
you know sort of side note into our new
media ecosystem and how powerful
you know citizen journalists info
militias is a word i've been using
uh you know groups of people surfacing
information making
making propaganda making information
films movies memes whatever
it really matters it really does matter
so keep it up guys keep it up out there
um all right so the treasury story is
what's up next
how did that come about and and what
happened
yeah i got actually multiple leaks from
the treasury department
and the related financial agencies
because they were doing these trainings
that were just
i mean absolutely outrageous and
uh and you know i'm trying to even think
of specifics
they all kind of blur together at this
point but um i mean
you know standard stuff like the united
states is a fundamentally racist country
um it can't redeem itself um you know uh
the
kind of like whiteness is the like
scourge on on the planet
and you know white cultural
characteristics are just cover for white
supremacy i mean like
the standard kind of litany of critical
race theory
kind of pseudoscientific claims um
and and they're just pushing it on like
i think i think
over the course of it definitely more
than 10 000 employees at the federal
financial agencies
damn and i got multiple people saying
hey this is
completely outrageous it's insulting it
has nothing to do with our job
we're trying to like you know this is
like the the treasury department
these are folks that like run the money
supply of the united states it's
quite an important position uh and
they're doing these like
race trainings where they're saying you
need to go in a safe space and
you know apologize about this and blah
blah blah and and
it's like it it the the documents were
just absolutely
shocking and uh and that and that blew
up and and you know i think uh
i think the i think that one actually
new york post picked up as an op-ed
um and then they put the kind of punchy
title on it you know that you can't
choose and they they really go nuts
right um but uh sometimes
the titles you know you got to get
people to click sometimes and
and i i myself have adopted the policy
of like
i will use the clickbaity title but i
promise it's all me
underneath so you got to get people to
take to take an action there but dude
i i one of the reasons i want to talk to
you is because i too have been working
on similar work and it's but per it's
been personal
so like you're describing these
trainings that's happening in
in the department of treasury and in
seattle and elsewhere
and i have lived it myself and i have
i've been fighting it when i
uh after i was executive director at uh
charter schools in dc i went to work for
the regulator the authorizer the charter
school authorizer and i was the top
finance manager
for for almost a billion dollars worth
of uh
charter schools right and so it was my
job to make sure that they were doing
everything they needed to do financially
right but as i'm getting onboarded there
it's clear that they have these
diversity inclusion and equity meetings
and they have
secret subcommittees and where they plan
out what the trainings are going to be
and i happened to come across uh
they gave me my predecessors emails
right so i'm going through the emails
looking for stuff that i need on another
subject and i come across
a picture of a whiteboard that was taken
what it was note-taking
for one of their diversity inclusion and
equity planning sessions and it was the
vision
of this organization which is a dc which
is quasi
federal agency managing charter schools
in district columbia
educators and it says right there on the
white board
there's too many white people working
here okay like
this is their like sanctioned secret
committee that's planning how they're
going to do their hiring
and their organization and whatnot and
around
uh this conversation that i stumbled
across in the email were
all these pre-meeting documents they
sent around and this was before white
fragility came out but it was definitely
deangelo's work right and it was all
the same stuff that we know about now
that you know also
all systems or sorry all black suffering
is due to systems of white oppression
and white supremacy is like punctuality
and science and data and rugged
individualism
and like perfectionism and like getting
things done
you know like all this crazy but
these were like
and i think you've probably seen this
too these were mostly
youngish to middle-aged white women who
had drank whatever this kool-aid was
and they are now evangelicals for it
and pushing it throughout the entire
system and through the entire
nation and i resisted in a staff meeting
i said
wait a second um i've done some research
i had been reading
jesse single at that point and he has
done great work on debunking
on debunking the implicit association
test and i like
you know i'm a big guy and i don't
usually be not very timid usually but i
timidly raise my hand and i'm like uh
you know the
the guy that created this test has
already said that it's not useful or
predictive and we shouldn't be doing
anything with it and they like they just
didn't care
nobody cared and eventually you know i
got fired from this institution
because they didn't like the fact that i
just thought differently
and when we talk later about this order
which says hostile work environments man
i sat there and lived through a hostile
work environment where they were
explicitly saying there's too many white
people working here
which just was blew my mind like you
dream about it
or you read about it and you think it's
not real and then you're sitting there
and you're experiencing it and you're
like but wait a second they say i can't
be
you know there's no such thing as racism
against white people
institutional racism wait this
institution is saying that white people
are bad we need to get rid of them
and nobody seemed to care and now
you know afterwards i have sent in foia
requests that they have now denied i'm
trying to get
everything i can out of there and
they're denying their foia
requests and putting them off due to
covid have you had any
uh difficulties i mean you sound like
you've been able to do document requests
and just get them
nobody's like who's been fighting and
people been fighting oh they're always
quiet man they always fight and uh
you know a lot of it is leaked though so
these are like whistleblower documents
so these are people on the inside who
i think agree with what i'm doing and
they say hey you're the guy
this is something that's happening
that's completely outrageous uh here's a
kind of
zip file full of the documents that show
what's happening and then
and then i'll do the kind of the
investigative work to call everyone at
the organization to confirm and to find
out
if they're you know legitimate and kind
of do the paper trail but
when you start with the actual documents
you're in a good place but on the on the
foia side yeah i've had people deny foia
requests that
i just did one for king county uh
washington or county
of seattle um and uh you know they
denied it for a long time as documents i
knew they had so then i just like spun
up some legal
kind of legal threats basically and said
hey if you do not give this to me now i
know you have it i will sue you
personally
and i will sue your agency and then 24
hours later they cough up all the
documents
i mean you know foia is uh is a process
that in theory works
well and you get everything but in
practice there's a lot of ways where
they can throw roadblocks in your way so
you have to just keep pushing
um but i i found on the document side
when you get
inside whistleblower documents those are
always a great place to start
and then you can follow up with uh you
know pdrs public document requests
when you get to where you are now you
become gra you're like a gravity point
you're like a black hole for
for uh for leaks and information and now
everybody wants to
get their information out and they see
you rightfully as a as a great conduit
with the from their lips to the
president's ears basically i mean what
an incredible position for you to be in
that a whistleblower in some county and
some state somewhere
can send you information about something
that they're experiencing that's
terrible that's hostile workplace that's
actual racism that's actually causing
them
it caused me i'll admit it it caused me
emotional distress
to be in an environment where
everybody's sitting around going you're
a racist just because you asked
this question
right like yeah and so these people now
have a way
citizens think social media god bless it
giveth and it taketh but in this case it
giveth
they got connected to you they send you
the documents you put it together you
run your stories
you call on the president to make change
i know
and here we are dude i know i know
it's kind of weird if you think about it
it's like a night and i feel bad almost
because
there's a lot of great people that have
been working on this issue for a long
time
and i feel like kind of like the new kid
on the block that like
comes in and just like you know puts in
a pretty low
effort 90 days and gets something
big done so i i i feel it is some guilt
i guess
but um but also i know that this work is
on is on the shoulders of a lot of great
people i mean
you know a lot of people you mentioned
have been working on this issue and laid
the foundation for this
and uh you know i was able to kind of
carry the ball the last couple yards um
but
there's been a ton of people on the left
on the right in the center
uh that see the threat uh that that kind
of
kind of unchecked wokism presents um and
then i think you know i guess like i
would say my role and
and uh my kind of what i brought that
was different is like i'm i'm just a
conservative
like i'm just a conservative you know i
think a lot of the problem is that
a lot of the kind of people who are like
oh maybe like disaffected
left they would never think of calling
on donald trump to do something about it
because it's just out of their kind of
cultural comfort zone
right um but it's like you know i'm
affiliated with discover institute in
seattle where i'm the research center
director
i'm affiliated with manhattan institute
and city journal conservative think tank
in new york
and now visiting fellow heritage
foundation the kind of most venerable
and largest conservative very kind of
establishment conservative think tank
um so it's like i have no compunction i
am who i am i
i i my friends are are my friends uh and
i think that that gave me maybe a bit
more of a kind of
a kind of risk reduction for the
political folks to say okay
this guy is for sure on our team um and
the people that are backing him the
people that are
are supporting this campaign uh the
people that are advocating
um if we have those people the kind of
conservative establishment is now waking
up to this threat and wants to take
action
we're safe to actually push on this um
so i think it really complemented a lot
of the work frankly from the people on
the kind of
old left uh that that offered the first
criticism
and then you know we were able to put it
into action uh
man you said a lot there um one thing
kudos to you for acknowledging that
a lot of this work is done on the
shoulders of people that have been
pressing on this issue for a while
uh i agree with that a hundred percent
uh
one person's name comes to mind is
jordan peterson he was somebody who
really was uh
instrumental in bringing this issue into
the dialogue in our little niches and
then blowing it up into a much
larger conversation i think a lot of us
owe some credit to him for
putting a a human face
an empathetic face and a real emotional
appeal
on these subjects and on the subject
matter uh it was one thing for me to be
writing my like
anti radical feminist screen blog stuff
in 2015
uh but then you know jordan peterson
does it with empathy and kindness and
compassion and
i think he inspired a lot of people to
take action and to push the
conversations along so
kudos to you for acknowledging that but
dude props to you though because
you you were like you raised the energy
level
and you had a goal and you had a target
and you had a mission
and you did it and you went and you
spoke and he made that call to action
right like that that is what people miss
is the call to action and
being persuasive enough to call someone
to action and get them to act
so you know kudos to you for that um
i'm impressed and i'm energized in
talking to you and just seeing that
in showing like what is possible if you
just take it even farther even another
step further and another step farther
and
and chunk it up even bigger into a
bigger issue
and and make bigger claims and put it in
in the right context
which is what i think that you have done
at the same time as giving voice
to the voiceless out there uh just
regular folks suffering
through this kind of nonsense which
truly is a form of emotional
abuse right it's gaslighting it's
telling you
that your own perceptive tools are
faulty that you see the world but you
see it incorrectly
and not only do you see it incorrectly
but you're flawed for it
and not only are you flawed for it but
here my job my federal employer job
i am here to brainwash you and beat you
over the head with a hammer
until you answer these questions the
right way
using the right words and we think that
you mean it and if you don't mean it
you're gonna have to go back through the
trainings again and you're gonna have to
regurgitate all this and it's a
struggle session it's a struggle session
that happens at work
it's happening in our children's schools
so i'm gonna rant for a second
in my kids schools in montgomery county
maryland i got a notice saying that they
were gonna have quote courageous
conversations and i look for
courageous conversations they're from
seattle yeah yeah and
and they're like we're just going to use
this creator's compass this courageous
conversations compass to have a talk
about
what happened in kenosha and jacob blake
and
kyle rittenhouse and i started to dig
into it and dude it is like the epitome
of critical race theory and one of the
things that they say right in this thing
they're giving to our teenagers is
you need to sit with your whiteness you
need to experience your whiteness and if
it makes you uncomfortable
good you're supposed to feel
uncomfortable don't listen to your
internal alarm bells don't listen to
your instincts saying that this is wrong
don't listen to your run away
that your mind telling you to run away
sit here and suffer
and do it until and as long as we
deem necessary to the point at which and
you know you've seen the stuff that was
posted in the smithsonian that light
blue like expanding bubble chart where
it's like
you're beginning work and your end work
and the end work is
i yield the the the anti-racist right
the goal of all this
is i yield positions of power to people
of color
that is the goal to yield positions of
power to people of color
simply because you are white
i hate talking about this race dude
i'm gen x i was raised
to be colorblind i was raised to judge
people on the contents of the character
and that's what i did my whole life and
i ignored all that until somebody
else said
hey buddy race is important now and it's
your race that's the issue
and in fact this whole country
is the issue because of you and your
people
and so what are we going to do you can't
just sit back
because they're coming for you and
they're coming for your children and
they're coming for your jobs
and they're coming for your government
that come for your universities
there's no ignoring it anymore there's
no
just hoping it goes away and
with the events of the summer and the
riots and the protests and
the statues and the arson and the
murders and antifa and black lives
matter
when i see it's the whole context
and in there is a direct attack on my
children
in their impressionable minds then
it's just it's too much man so i'm doing
my best to see what we can do about that
in montgomery county also in washington
dc
as well and uh all right there that's
the end of my rant
okay so you know i i would add one point
because i think it's a really important
one and it's one that i kind of end up
on and
you know i did a film uh for pbs uh
about
three of america's poorest cities uh
it's called america lost uh
we can send a link to your to your
viewers they can watch it for free
um uh before it comes out on tv but what
was your name again
america lost and it's locked okay yeah
and i'll send a link out that you can
you can send out but you know i spent
really three years of field production
kind of five years total
um just spending time and understanding
the poorest neighborhoods in memphis
tennessee in stockton california and
youngstown ohio
multiracial kind of mostly white
community in memphis mostly black
community
actually almost exclusively black
community in in
memphis and then a kind of latino and
multiracial community in
stockton california and the the thing
about critical race theory that i think
is
is is probably the point that people
don't say but i think to me is the most
important point is that
critical race theory does absolutely
nothing
to help kind of ethnic minorities and
racial minorities
in america's poorest neighborhoods um
in fact it actually is a deeply
pessimistic and deeply destructive
ideology
because it tries to teach that there's
nothing you can do to be successful
everyone's out to get you uh hard work
and showing up on time is actually white
supremacy
you know in all of the ways that
throughout kind of
history and and thomas soul has done
great work on this
that that minority groups and immigrant
groups you know my father included
were able to become successful the kind
of formula that actually
you know works over time they're really
trying to demolish all of those
foundational kind of pillars uh you know
they're saying the family the nuclear
family is just white supremacy it's like
well actually
uh if if you have a two-parent household
um compared to a single-parent household
your chances of being in poverty are
like stratospherically different
and and actually what what here's the
thing
critical race theory serves the
interests of a kind of
multi-racial progressive elite it gets
people
university appointments it gets them
aspen institute presentation it gets
them
you know kudos for the new yorker but it
actually is deeply destructive
to racial and ethnic minorities in
america's poor cities
and uh and and that to me is the
greatest moral crime
of critical race theory uh it's
something that i saw i
i i i kind of walked with these folks
for five years
i really understood the communities from
the inside out and i can tell you that
um
critical race theory has nothing to
offer in a way that's constructive in a
way that
that helps people reach their full
potential in a way that expresses the
values of freedom and equality
and that's why i'm going to fight
against it with everything i got i
couldn't agree with you
more in my experience as an education
professional in washington dc
i had a lot of chance to look at discuss
describe
analyze and think about the achievement
gap
the difference in education outcomes
achieved by people of varying races and
socioeconomics
and the scary thing that i found with
critical race theory is that
it takes all of the onus off of
educators students and families
their their outcomes are no longer their
responsibility
so i would see time and time again
people coming to testify in front of our
authorizer saying oh well you know our
scores aren't good enough because you
know
the system right like we can't help
these kids
they're coming from the system the
system is flawed it's a racist system
blah blah blah blah blah all it means is
that the families the students the
schools the teachers and the principals
don't have to take responsibility for
the outcomes and what i have been
harping on uh
myself for years about the achievement
gap is that
it distracts us from the real issues and
the real issues are difficult
they're huge they're they start at home
it's
family issues it's a mother's education
it's the zip code in which people live
in
and it's not about the fact that like
your science teacher
supports donald trump and therefore he's
like holding you back it's just not
right
and it distracts people from the issue
at hand
and then we just throw more money at it
and more money at it and it just
the distraction itself becomes even
bigger and then the real losers
the number one losers are minority
children
mostly in the cities and they're not
being given
the the person who is up there who's
already sort of made it out you know
they're not reaching their hand back
and saying look this is how you get up
the ladder dude follow me this is what
we do
now they're just like burn the whole
ladder down throw the ladder it
there's no way we can get out of here so
let's just burn the whole thing down
and uh that was a question that people
always bring up is like
okay so if all these things are white
supremacy
like individualism being on time data
science like basically america the
american
way right or western way if all these
things are white supremacy
like what is the opposite like what are
we going to replace it with
with like being laid and not focusing on
data and not looking at it and these
people don't
mean any of it that's the other thing
these people don't mean any of it the
people who are putting up the charts
that showing up on time is white
supremacy guaranteed they show up on
time
right when at the faculty meeting or an
appointment or a grant you know
distribution right that's the other
thing this stuff is deeply phony and
brings me back to the
our first point of the conversation when
i'm sitting in college and realizing
these kind of like radical elites are
completely ridiculous
phony people it's the same thing and i
think that like almost it's almost like
you can't even debate the ideas because
they're so stupid
and just kind of degraded intellectual
thinking
you have to just say you don't even
believe that really
okay show up late to your job now show
up
15 minutes late from now on you know and
they couldn't do it
right there's no way they could do it
objectivity okay let's get rid of
objectivity
you know let's see how that works math
they're saying math as white supremacist
and it's like oh really that's quite
interesting uh because
my oldest son who is half asian happens
to be a top 1
math student am i going to explain to
him that actually this is his uh
his white supremacy emerging like i
think this stuff is all ridiculous and
it's like almost
you know i think there's a time and
place for serious debate but there's a
time and place just to throw our hands
up and say
i don't accept it well that's dishonest
that's the thing james lindsay's done
god's work in trying to
debate and debunk and to work with all
this and explain it and whatever
but at some point man you have to just
punch a dude in the face
literally not literally guys
figuratively out there you just have to
fight back
you have to fight back because i've made
this mistake in relationships and other
in the past where
you keep trying to apply a rational lens
to irrational behavior
yeah and you're like but that doesn't
make any sense why would they do that i
don't understand that
and and there's no arguing in your way
out of it there's no convincing them
and they're hitting you over the head
with a sledgehammer already so at this
point that's all there is left to do
is to fight back and that's what we're
doing that's what you're doing that's
what you've been doing
and the result of it and this is i want
to get into the meat of this now
the trump executive order that was just
released i'm going to show
we've got let's see let's see if i can
do it here we've got chris's website
uh this is um his latest article
president signs executive order
abolishing critical race theory
uh you can find uh chris on twitter at
realchrisrufo
and so this is where chris laid out what
he has been describing today
uh all this is on twitter as well and
now let's get into
the executive order so chris tell me
describe the executive order
describe what happened what you see
let's just go through it
and and what is it going to do and and
and you know what are the expected or
hope for outcomes here
yeah so um you know i'll i'll pull it up
here on my side too
because my it's been so exciting my
brain is kind of operating at
70 um so you know i'll kind of give you
the main points
and uh you know first off the the
president has done something i think
quite extraordinary he's now really
framing this election
on critical race theory 1619 project
riots
which are all kind of like unified under
the same ideology
versus the declaration of independence
which is a very claremontian theme
right um and uh and he's really going
there and i i think it's you know he
gave a speech at the national archives
i guess last week on this theme
denouncing critical race theory by name
and he basically does the same thing
here he says you know critical race
theory um
is a false and pernicious and false
belief that undermines the american
ideal that all men are created equal
um so he kind of sets the kind of
philosophical framework there
uh and then he basically says hey this
ideology is
this malign ideology is now migrating
from the fringes of american society and
threatens to affect core institutions of
our country
uh the the the writers very very kindly
cited a bunch of my reporting on the
issue for specifics
uh and then he gets into really what's
happening and uh
this is again something he he went the
white house team to their credit
their enormous credit went well beyond
uh even the initial omb
memo or my initial call to action and
they're basically saying
the federal funds cannot go to any
institution that supports critical race
theory
so critical race theory can no longer
happen in federal agencies it can no
longer happen in the military
and then the third thing which is really
key it can no longer happen in
corporations that are federal
contractors
and this is important because i would
say a majority of fortune 500 companies
at least are actually federal
contractors
um so it's in the executive order is
written in a way and a confirmed uh
intent with the white house if you are
like a microsoft or an amazon or a
or a you know walmart or whatever i
don't know any kind of big corporation
that does government contracting
after 60 days 60 days from yesterday you
can no longer teach critical race theory
programs anywhere in your company
private side or public sector side
because it is now a requirement to do
business with the federal government
you cannot be teaching these uh
anti-american principles
um and then a couple other hard hitters
he said hey
um he's instructing all of his agency
heads to say no more grants
that support critical race theory and i
think the real target here is academia
so the national science science
foundation and
and the other kind of humanities
endowments arts endowments
can no longer distribute money to
projects that are based on critical race
theory um so that's
that academic spigot is closed no does
that mean um
i understand what the corporations it's
like if the corporations are engaging
this stuff you can't do business with
the us government
but does this mean that like let's say
for example uh high schools across the
country they get a lot of them get title
one funding
um you know in in poor low income areas
and then they
they get title one funding that's for
specific things but then they also at
the same time
are pushing this uh you know critical
race theory based initiatives within
their schools
does that mean that they can't get the
title one funding anymore or no
this this on my reading and again uh you
know
i confirmed uh this wouldn't cover that
in my view
um it really is contractors or direct
expenditures so the actual grant federal
grant money can't support directly a
critical race theory
a program but here's the big kind of
asterisk that is uh
in section eight of the memo of the
executive order rather
he instructs the attorney general and uh
hopefully the attorney general will be
around for a little bit uh
you know four more years to implement it
to assess whether critical race theory
trainings create a hostile work
environment and constitute a violation
of the title of title vii of the civil
rights act
this is big um because peter kirsten ah
uh who's on the u.s civil rights
commission and others
um have basically said these are kind of
you know your race is a protected class
right you can't discriminate on the
basis of race
you can't kind of harass someone or
retaliate against someone on the basis
of race
and these programs and trainings are
likely violations
of the civil rights act um so he is
opening the legal floodgates and
i think the next step in this campaign
is really to recruit a network of
lawyers
that will file suits um anywhere and
everywhere
um to get the case law and to get the
precedent to
to say that these are actually uh
hostile work environments
uh they violate uh title vii they create
kind of uh
a a a kind of racial that constitutes a
form of racial harassment
um so i think that that is really the
big next step and i think that could be
big for a couple reasons um because uh a
you can kind of uh you know directly win
those cases
uh you can set the precedent and the
case law but also
corporations and even to a certain
extent universities are very risk-averse
so if we raise the cost of doing this
stuff i think their hr departments and
legal departments will quickly say uh
it's not worth the risk let's can all
these programs so i i think that
the the president's team is really
trying to figure out what are the levers
of power that we control
and how can we shift the incentives for
our major institutions
to to doing these things and this is
going after the bureaucracy it's going
after schools and universities
and it's going after increasingly our
kind of woke uh corporations
i'm pumped dude i'm so excited when i
hear these things
yes by god it creates a hostile work
environment
i mean i remember just sitting there and
just feeling bad
like just just because i was white
it's it's insane it is a hostile work
environment and
and and what's funny is these same
people will have turned around
and and beforehand said that you know
their their their preferred tool was to
say oh you're creating a hostile
microwork environment
but you know the truth is whatever they
accuse you of is what they're doing
themselves already so
i for one like for example in the super
chat here we had uh megan
megan asks you know like my child's
school started an anti-racism program
and i don't know how to start
obstructing it like what should i do how
do i go the distance here
how do i win and uh you know i think
it's very difficult thing to do on an
individual level but now that the
president has tied it
you know directly from his executive
order
he's empowering the intern attorney
general to take action
tying it to title vii and civil rights
and hostile work environment and hostile
you know sort of uh um you know
violating protected classes
that's a good vector like if you're
going to go to these meetings you got to
go to the meetings first of all
you got to go to the meetings and show
up where these things get decided
especially in your schools in the pta
and at the school board meetings and the
equity committee meetings and stuff and
you have to say
maybe bring it up you know this is what
the president is talking about
is this a violation of civil rights you
know and just
get that like people do get scared when
lawsuits can start flying and money
starts happening and
and and you know the risk level gets
raised i think for too long all these
people thought that they were just
had a free ride they could do whatever
they wanted they could say whatever they
wanted they could take whatever action
they wanted without any consequences and
of course because they believe
that they're fighting a religious war a
moral war that they're the ones who are
right everyone that opposes
are wrong and immoral and really even
like
sub-human right like how can you be a
human being if you
you know aren't anti-racist right and of
course to be anti-racist now means you
can't even
quote unwittingly participate in a
system that reinforces black oppression
like so you just walk down the street
you don't know what's going on and buddy
you're a racist and so
it's so dumb like the logic of that i
was thinking about that the other day
it's like
you know there's no such thing as not
racist that's a new thing you can't be
not racist you're either
anti-racist so you're either a political
and ideological progressive
or you're racist it's like oh really
well guess what
um what are you doing to actively combat
lyme disease
oh oh nothing oh well then you love when
people die of lyme disease you monster
you know it's like it's so it's like
it's like it's such a basic kind of
kind of logical idiocy and and yet it's
being
pumped at the highest levels of media at
the highest levels academia at the
highest levels of
the federal bureaucracy and it's like i
i find myself
feeling like we're increasingly in some
kind of
kind of soft totalitarian regime where
you know all of the official organs of
the state and the culture are telling
you one thing
that is so preposterous on its face and
yet people are being
socially pressured to comply um that
that it's like
it's it's too much and i think that what
we're finding now certainly the
president has elevated this to the
national stages
people are starting to say no i don't
agree that's enough is enough this is
this is wrong i'm going to fight it i'm
going to resist it
and and i think once we push on these
people
intellectually kind of their arguments
start to crumble because they're very
kind of foundationally weak and then
institutionally
uh they start to kind of hide and
and and get scared and kind of pull back
and uh and that's what i told you know i
told
dave rubin yesterday or a couple days
ago i guess i said
you know why do we have the attitude
that we can't win
like i don't believe that like i know
for sure that we can win
i'm not even i don't even think it's
gonna be that hard you know he's like
what you know so
it's like you you and and obviously it
will be hard it's it's everywhere blah
blah blah but
the attitude that we have to have is
that we are confident of victory
we are confident that we are kind of
morally justified we are confident that
we are intellectually justified
and we are confident that our position
will win and i think that's the attitude
that we have to have and i think the
days
i think like part of it is like these
terms right these epithets you're racist
you're white supremacist you're a
sexist you're a transphobic you're
whatever like their whole
the whole litany of them five years ago
was like oh my god i'm terrified two
years ago three years ago
i like my whole life is over somebody
called me this even if it's totally out
of bounds totally unfair totally
inaccurate
the power of those words was enough to
deter
any real resistance from most people
yeah
those words have been debased and
degraded to such an extent that they
don't mean anything anymore
i mean you have articles that are saying
square dancing is white supremacist
math is white supremacist logic is white
supremacist
it's like uh okay well i guess
this word actually has lost any meaning
and any power so
yeah the the the the kind of asymmetry
is now
flipped where those words used to be an
ex like an atom bomb level power
now they're kind of like a street
sweeper that are just kind of shuffling
around in the background trying to clean
things up
so we have an opportunity rhetorically
and in our kind of cultural vocabulary
to now take the dominant position and to
push on these people
and to have much less fear of the kind
of insults and epithets that might come
our way
dude beautifully said beautifully said i
remember reading in 2017 or so
jordan hall who's a very excellent
futurist and philosopher and a former
tech guy
he wrote about something called the the
red the resistance of the red religion
and basically what he's saying is that
the blue church which is the deep state
and
and the resistance and all these guys
have have have taken a scorched earth
policy
called everyone a racist tried to kill
everybody by using these horrible
insults which
god i mean it i still have visceral
memories of
when that word held weight right like i
that was like the last thing you ever
wanted to be called
totally yeah it's worse it was the worst
and and
now they've used it so much that the
only thing that's left standing
are people that are resistant to that
and like you just can't it's like a
a bacteria that can't be killed by
antibiotics or whatever like we just
can't you just can't kill us with that
anymore it's done
and so the earth has been scorched we
are the only ones left standing and now
we're going to push back and now we're
going to
take the fight to them um do you think
that this election this 2020 election
is woke versus not is it
is it the is it the north versus the
white the woke walkers like
is this the and is this the struggle is
this what the decision is
is this what the election is about now
yeah well yeah and i'll give you some
background
you know i i didn't vote for uh donald
trump in 2016.
um i kind of i just couldn't do it i
couldn't vote for hillary i couldn't
vote for trump i just kind of was torn
and
and i ended up just completely wasting
my vote on gary johnson just as kind of
like a
kind of a safety valve an easy out i'm
sure honestly probably many people
listening are in the same boat
um because i had those reservations
right in a way to kind of i said oh
donald trump you know this guy and i
don't know and
and he's kind of a wild card and he's
going to be this he sent me that
but a couple things happened that i
think um
started changing my mind one is that he
actually tried to keep or kept
most of the promises on the campaign
trail he's delivered conservative
supreme court justices
um he uh he has uh
not fought any new wars i mean which is
like an achievement that i think dates
back to the 1970s
right he's the only president since what
maybe carter um to not
launch any new wars um and then i i
think that this
for me the last you know month
sealed the deal because he's i think
very much framed the election
as kind of woke-ism versus the american
way of life and
there you go and and you know i mean
cool like i feel like
like kind of amazed it's like wow i had
some part in this framing because
the last you know he was gonna run on
the kind of economy right
the economy is great everyone's happy
look at your 401k you're making more
money than ever unemployment's low
the coronavirus wiped out that rationale
and i think and then the riots happen
and i think you saw him kind of with the
virus and the riots and the economy very
uncertain for a period
and then i think everything clicked in
this campaign where he said actually
all these things are connected the 1619
project
critical race theory trainings the riots
on the streets
they're all the black lives matter kind
of more extreme ideologies
they're all rooted in this world view
that is not rooted in any american
tradition it's rooted in a european
tradition and a marxist tradition
um it's rooted in the kind of identity
politics emerging from the frankfurt
school
and and and it is a threat to the
american way of life the american regime
the american system that has
for its faults of course we have to
admit always move steadily towards
equality and freedom and i think that
kind of
once that clicked and then i think maybe
this critical race theory trainings gave
him another
kind of tangible thing to hold on to
the speech at the national archives
which i recommend everyone listen to um
the the the speeches he's giving and
during the campaigns this executive
order
uh fighting against 1619 project he's
really framing this election
as a very simple choice do you want to
preserve the american way of life or do
you want to burn it down
indeed that's the question and when that
is the question
for me i have one answer and it's like i
want to preserve the system
i want to improve it i want to
acknowledge our past uh flaws and
imperfections like every society has
but ultimately america is worth fighting
for the american principles are correct
they've enabled us to have a country for
almost 250 years
uh that has some of the most astonishing
achievements from people of all
different backgrounds
um i mean you know we we
we went to put a man to the moon we
invented the airplane we invented the
automobile we invented the personal
computer we invented jazz we invented
hip-hop we invented rock and roll
uh these are things that are not kind of
trivial
uh trivial accomplishments these are
kind of world historical things
that have emerged from our system uh and
uh and we produced the great literature
from frederick douglass to martin luther
king to
uh to to to to the great writers of the
20th century
and um and and to me that's something
that's worth saving and i just feel like
the
the energy on the left is to burn it all
down
with this kind of naive hope that when
you destroy something
something naturally better will emerge
and i think that is the height of
of naivete and i think it's the height
of folly
yeah wow very well said chris i really
appreciate that
um and i do appreciate you acknowledging
sort of your own political evolution and
i know that there's been
a number of people who saw i always want
to talk to eric weinstein about this
who saw the the the risks
that you know social justice and
critical race theory have played
or have have posed to western
civilization
like legit straight up risk to western
in my book i called a vote for donald
trump a vote to save western
civilization
and yet they were unwilling
or unable or some reason to say in 2016
like oh western civilization worth
saving why don't i vote for this guy
that says
yay america or on the other team it's
like no boo america
right that's what it basically is coming
down to uh and
so i'm happy to see a number of people
at least
leaving the left and saying all right i
can't support that anymore
and they have to go through their own
process to where they can finally
assess the risk the various risk
elements that you have to assess when
you're going to pick a precedent
and and finally come to acknowledge that
critical race theory black lives matter
antifa
radical feminism intersectionality all
of this
poses an actual existential risk to the
republic
to the american experiments to western
civilization
to our future developments because our
system is the one that creates the
development the technological advances
the cultural advances etc
we risk just throwing all that away
uh because kimberly crenshaw decided to
make her maps of you know intersectional
oppression or whatever in the 80s
and here we are it's carried through all
the way to this point so i
call on all of you fence sitters out
there the ones that can
see the problem who assess the risk but
are unwilling to take the
steps necessary to protect the republic
and protect western civilization
you know i'm kind of tired of you free
riders to be honest
i took a big risk man i got arrows in my
back i got
shot up i got docked i got swatted i got
banned from coaching little league
got time taken away from my kids my
family got damaged all because i took a
risk
hey buddy take a risk protect the
american
way of life in america western
civilization protect the republic
this is it 2020 maybe one of the last
chances we have
if if trump loses in november biden
takes over this eo goes in the waste
basket
all this gets looked upon as if it
were just a blip
uh a momentary you know disruption and
now not only
are they gonna throw it away but then
they're going to do everything they can
to quote make sure this never happens
again make sure there was never
another another trump make sure all
these trumpets get what's coming to them
we got to do whatever you know throw
some gulags or whatever
metaphorical or literal who knows at
this point
you know and and so is it if we want to
see this continue if we want this
momentum to continue
we got to vote for trump in 2020. i
believe that the american people the
more that they understand what's
happening
the more they're gonna support this in
my book i interviewed hundreds of people
did his national survey like 1500 people
responded
with 15 questions each 1500 responses of
short answer questions where i read i
read like 15 000 paragraphs from people
and they all have a sense they know oh i
can't say this thing or i can't do that
thing or
why is that man who is now a woman
beating up this other woman in an mma
cage
like they have the sense something is
wrong but they you know hadn't been able
to put a
you know like put a target on something
and you sir
have helped all of us put the target
where it needs to go
you have been like the the the cider i
don't know what the technical term is
the spotter i guess
yeah and you're like you're like over
here mr president you know
turn the guns over this way and the
machine
and then boom zero in right in
and uh i'm just super excited i'm like
you know we we really have just started
talking for the first time today but
we've crossed paths for a while on
twitter i'm proud of you dude
like thank you like way to go man and
like on a personal level it must be so
satisfying to see
this alignment with your work and your
mission and your values and and the
country and the national stories and
sort of like a singularity all happening
for you all at once and real things
happening so congratulations
i appreciate that yeah it really is that
it feel like everything
kind of clicked in and honestly all
these things were really kind of
chance kind of very improbable things
that all happened in this kind of
intricate succession um that that
at any one point it could all gone off
the rails and and this wouldn't have
happened so i i feel like wow just you
know
blessed and and uh just fortunate and
kind of you know
kind of divinely inspired because it's
like wow this all happened and uh it's
great thing and
you know i'm told too this is kind of a
fun tidbit but um
i'm told that uh there is a package
coming my way and the president is
sending me the pen that he used to sign
the executive order
so that to me is like a cool little like
a token of this victory and uh
it's gonna be right up there and you
know one of the things here um you'll
see here is actually
uh it looks like a just a rock uh
spray-painted concrete but it's actually
a piece of the berlin wall
oh fantastic yeah my grandmother was
there actually when the wall came down
in west germany
on vacation with my grandfather and uh
they took a pickaxe to the wall and they
brought home a couple chunks
for us and uh and i keep that there
because i
i feel like you can never forget what it
like what it's like to live in a
repressive regime
and it's a reminder that um you know
people the kind of institutions can
build walls but we can also tear them
down
and right across from it will be that
pen you know to show the power of public
policy the power of language the power
of the pen
uh and then of course a great compliment
to the power of my
of my emoji of choice the crossed swords
it's all fun man yeah the emoji of
choice swords up dude
and and like i i love that i um
i'm trying i'm tying it also with like
wartime conservatives
like we can meme we're going to meme
this into a real big thing like
swords up for sure no no time to sit
back
time to fight time to fight man yeah and
it's fun and it's like you know it's
it's tongue-in-cheek it's ironic it's
kind of
it's funny but like we have to have fun
too like that's the thing i can i can
feel it in you i know you're having a
great time you're having fun you're
enjoying it
and we have to get people through that
wall of fear uh to the point where your
courage is grounded
and then you can kind of take on the
monster you know because you've been
through it and i think we need more
leaders and uh
cultural leaders and political leaders
that that can get there and kind of
stand with us and and fight
because uh it's like there's nothing
more beautiful than being in the middle
of some huge melee uh and just trying to
fight your way out
and being on the right side of history
you know for sure and fighting your way
out so
uh tremendous work amazing conversation
thank you so much chris congratulations
to you
guys you're listening out there please
go to realchrisrufo on twitter
go to christopherruffo.com sign up for
his mailing list join his patreon
support his work
listeners to jack murphy live please hit
subscribe wherever you are whether it's
on youtube
on spotify on itunes or iheartradio
or stitch or wherever else hit subscribe
um
thank you so much chris i really
appreciate it i can't wait to talk to
you again
in a couple of weeks or a month or so
see where this thing goes
we'll certainly stay in touch through
the election and whatever
drama comes out of the election you know
whatever it's going to be like november
3rd to january
uh who knows what's really going to
happen there so congratulations guys
everybody go check out christopher
ruffo.com
at realchrisrufo on twitter support the
cause if you've got any information
about critical race theory um
trainings or programs or implementations
in your organization or your government
you know agency or whatever send them
off to chris send them off to me let's
get them out there
let's let's expose them for what they
are and get this taken out of our
institutions our schools and everywhere
else
thank you very much chris and uh i will
talk to you very soon buddy thanks a lot
bye-bye